（綱手）カカシ。　風影からお前に
部隊長就任の打診があった。
Kakashi…
The Kazekage suggested
that you be appointed
a troop commander.
（カカシ）なぜ　俺に？
Why me?
第三次忍界大戦において
神無毘橋の戦いでの実績がある。
You took part in the battle
of Kannabi Bridge
during the Third Great Ninja War.
どの里も
第三次忍界大戦を経験した者は→
There aren't many veterans left
from that war in any village.
少なくなっているからな。
これは　私からの命令でもある。
This is also
a direct order from me.
それなら　断る理由はありません。
Then I guess I can't refuse.
ただ　ひとつお願いが。
なんだ？
However, I have one request.
What is it?
戦争は１人ではできません。
One man can't wage a war.
私の右腕となり
働いてくれる忍が必要です。
I need a shinobi as
my right-hand man to assist me.
うむ…　お前が信頼できる
忍というのは誰だ？
Is there someone that
you trust implicitly?
今　その男は
ナルトの護衛の任についています。
That man is presently on
a mission escorting Naruto.
それは…。
That would be…
カメカメ…。
Turtle, turtle!
これは…
緊急の際の　ガイの忍亀です。
This is…
Guy's ninja tortoise that
he only uses in an emergency!
（ガイ）カ～ッ　ペッ！　プハッ…。
一段落ついたか。
At last! It's calmed down!
（アオバ）もう　いいんですか？
ハハッ　なんのなんの。
Are you all right now?
Not to worry.
These waves are nothing.
これしきの波
どうってことないわ。
航海中
ずっと船酔いが続いてるのに→
He's been seasick during
this whole journey.
まだ強がりを。
And he's still acting tough.
Well, since we're all here…
（ヤマト）では　揃ったところで
早速ですが…。
水の国領内の離島で
最後の補給をしたら→
We'll be entering the seas off
of the Land of Lightning
after we make a final stop
to replenish our supplies
すぐに　雷の国の海域に入ります。
on this isolated island
in the Land of Water.
（アオバ）第４コーナーを
まわったってところかな。
So we've turned the last corner.
油断は禁物。
敵は　心の隙を突いてくるもの。
Complacency is
our greatest enemy.
The enemy will seek
any opportunity to attack.
だが　ここまでくれば→
But…
Since we're this close,
we can call for backup
何かあっても　忍連合軍から
援軍が来てくれるだろう。
from the Allied Shinobi Forces
if anything happens.
その援軍が　敵の変化した
者たちかもしれませんよ。
But those reinforcements
could be transformed enemies.
なに！？
例えば　綱手様とかカカシ先輩。
What?!
Even if it's people we know well,
like Lady Tsunade or Kakashi,
ごく身近な人間でも
決して　気を緩めないことです。
we mustn't let our guard down.
ま　まさか…。
N-No way!
上忍たるもの　チャクラを感じ
見抜けぬようでどうする！
If we jonin can't even distinguish
their chakra, what good are we?
噂ですが…。
I've heard a rumor that
there's a Transformation Jutsu
近頃　チャクラまでもコピーする
変化の術があるそうですよ。
that can copy and transform chakra.
な　なんと！
W-What?!
お～い。
Hey.
おぉ！　我が永遠のライバル　カカシ！
Oh! My eternal rival, Kakashi!
う～む…　くわばら　くわばら。
Oh, knock on wood…
knock on wood!
それと　くれぐれも
この任務の真の目的を→
And…
let me emphasize
that Naruto must not learn
ナルトには悟られないように。
the real purpose of this mission.
特に　ガイさん。
わかっておるわ。
I'm talking to you, Guy.
I know! This S-rank mission
is just a cover!
Ｓ級任務とは　真っ赤なウソ。
実は　この航海は
ナルトを守るための…。
We are here to protect Naruto.
（ナルト）ふぁ～。
Gotta hurry!
急げ～っと。
♪ 「フフン　フフ～ン」
いけ　螺旋オシッコ！　そりゃそりゃ。
Go! Rasen-pee!
あぁ…。
ん？　あれ？
Hey, what're you all doing together
this late at night?
こんな夜更けに
みんな揃って何してるの？
何って…　マッサージだ　マッサージ。
What? Well, I'm getting a massage.
マッサージ？
おうよ。
A massage?
Yup!
決して　ナルト抜きの密談などは…。
We totally weren't leaving you
out of a secret—!
みんな　まさか　俺に内緒で…。
Hey, you wouldn't be…
なんか　うまいもん隠してんだろ！
hiding something delicious
from me?!
だろ？　だろ？　そうなんだろ？
Are you? Are you?!
うまいものがあったら
ちゃんと　ナルトにも声をかけるよ。
If we had something delicious,
we'd let you know.
おやすみ。
Good night.
今後の航海スケジュールについて
話し合ってただけだよ。
We were just discussing
the remaining schedule.
ガイさん　あとは頼みましたよ。
Guy, please take care of the rest.
おぉ…　おうよ！
見張りは任せておけ。
Okay!
You can count on me
to stand watch!
う～ん…
な～んか怪しいってばよ。
Something funny is going on here.
ふぁ～。
見張りは　俺だけで十分だ。
お前は　もう寝たらどうだ？
I can keep watch by myself.
Why don't you get some sleep?
やることなくて
昼間から寝てるから→
I've had nothing to do
except sleep during the day.
眠れねえんだってばよ。
So I can't fall asleep now.
里のみんな
今ごろ　何してんのかな…。
I wonder what everyone
in the village is up to?
カカシ先生とも
もう　ずいぶん会ってねえし。
I haven't seen Kakashi Sensei
in quite a while.
あぁ　カカシか…。　人は　こう呼ぶ。
Kakashi, huh.
People call him
Might Guy's eternal rival!
マイト・ガイの永遠のライバルだと。
いい機会だ。　若き日々の話など
聞かせてやろうか。
This is a good opportunity to
tell you about our younger days.
別にいいってばよ。
You don't really have to…
２人のライバル関係が始まったのは→
Our rivalry began right around
the time we first became genin.
俺が　まだ
下忍になりたての頃だった。
別にいいってばよ…。
You don't really have to tell me.
どけ。　陰になる。
Move, you're in my light.
俺　人呼んで
木ノ葉の碧い猛獣　マイト・ガイ！
People call me Might Guy,
the Leaf's Blue Beast!
君って　木ノ葉の白い牙
サクモさんの息子で超エリートなんだろ？
Aren't you one of
the super elite?
You're the White Fang of the Leaf,
Sakumo's son, right?
だったら　どうした？
What about it?
悪い癖で　天性の才に
恵まれてるやつを見ると→
I have a bad habit.
Whenever I see a guy
with innate talent,
チャレンジしたくなるんだ。
I get the urge to challenge him!
どうだい？　俺と　青春をかけた
熱い勝負をしないか？
So? How about we lay our youth on
the line for a hot-blooded battle?
ムダなことは　したくない。
I don't like doing things
I don't have to do.
君が天性のエリートなら
俺は努力のエリートだ。
You were born an elite,
whereas I am elite
through sheer effort!
すばらしいライバル関係に
なれると思うんだけどな。
I think we could have
an amazing rivalry.
フッ　冗談も
そこまでいくと笑えないね。
Your humor leaves me speechless.
おっ　おい！　勝負の件は！？
Hey!
What about my challenge?
断る。
I refuse!
うん！
ますます　やる気が出てきたぞ！
That makes me even
more determined!
一度決めたことは　あきらめない！
それが俺の自分ルールだ。
I never back down
once I make up my mind.
That's my own rule!
勝負しようぜ！
Let's fight!
勝負！
ドングリ。
It's like an acorn.
ぐぅ～！　勝負だ　カカシ！
Fight me, Kakashi!
嫌だってば。
I don't want to!
フゥ…。
勝負！
Fight me!
ついに
俺の熱い青春の熱意に負けて→
Kakashi finally succumbed to
the intensity of my passionate,
youthful determination
and accepted my challenge.
カカシも　チャレンジを受けてくれた。
カカシ先生　かわいそ…。
I feel bad for Kakashi Sensei.
それから　ライバル競争の歴史は
綴られていくことになったわけだ。
And that's how we forged
our bond of rivalry.
勝負の中身も怪しいな　こりゃ。
Yeah, but I wonder about
the kind of fights you had.
何を言うか！　いずれも
正々堂々とした真剣勝負なんだぞ。
What are you saying?!
We gave it our all with
honest, serious battles.
《まぁ　確かに
語りづらいとこもあるがな》
Although I must admit,
I'm hesitant to describe
some of them.
弓矢　鎖がま　手裏剣
すべて　俺の勝ちだ。
Bow and arrow,
sickle and chain, shuriken.
I beat you in all of them.
もう　気は済んだろ？
Satisfied?
まだだ！
直接　組み手で勝負だ！
Not yet! I challenge you
to a sparring match!
体術なら　お前に負けない！
If it's taijutsu,
I won't lose to you!
豪語するだけのことは
あるようだな！
It seems you have enough
to brag about.
さすが　木ノ葉の白い牙の
才を継ぐ天才。
A prodigy indeed,
with skills inherited from
the White Fang of the Leaf!
逃げ足は速いな！
He is so quick to run away!
重い…。
It's heavy!
木ノ葉旋風！
Leaf Hurricane!
You're mine!
もらった！
ハッハッハ！　ちょっと
やりすぎちゃったかなぁ。
Maybe I overdid it a little!
変わり身！？
A substitution ?!
フン　もう　これで懲りたろ。
Have you had enough now?
これからは　身の程を知るんだな。
From now on,
just know your place.
離せ　クズ。
Let go, you scum!
嫌だ…。
まだ　俺の挑戦は終わってない。
No. I'm not finished
challenging you yet.
逃げるな！　俺は　クズじゃない！
Don't run away. I'm not scum.
すべての勝負は
やり尽くしただろ。
I've beaten you in every challenge.
次は…　何で勝負するんだ？
What did you have in mind next?
いくぞ～！
こい！
Here I go!
Come on!
– Rock, paper, scissors!
じゃんけんぽん！
あいこでしょ！　しょ！
– Again! Again! Again! Again!
しょ！　しょ！　しょ！
《なかには　そういう対決も
あったということは→
I won't say anything about
challenges like that one.
黙っておこう》
俺　やっぱ寝ることにするわ。
I think I'll go to sleep,
after all.
Hey, the good part
is just beginning.
おい…　これからが
いいところなんだがなぁ。
Man… I'm starting
to get sleepy too.
いかん…　俺も眠くなってきたぞ。
（カカシ）ガイ！　お～い！
Guy!
Hey!
（カカシ）ガイ！
Guy!
誰か呼んだかな？
（カカシ）こっち　こっち。
Did someone just call my name?
Over here! Over here!
おぉ　カカシではないか。
Oh, it's you, Kakashi!
いやぁ　しかし
なんで　こんな海の上に？
Huh? Why are you out on the water?
イテッ　夢でもない。　もしや…。
Ouch!
It's not a dream.
Could it really be?
((カカシ先輩とか
ごく身近な人間の格好をして→
They can disguise themselves
as someone we know very well,
like Kakashi,
(チャクラまでもコピーする変化の術が…))
and even copy his chakra
with a Transformation Jutsu.
《これが
ヤマトが言ってた　変化の術か。
Could this be
the Transformation Jutsu
that Yamato spoke of?
だまされてなるものか。
I won't be fooled.
敵を　ナルトに
近づけるわけにもいかんしな。
I cannot allow the enemy
to get near Naruto.
What nerve to disguise himself
as my eternal rival!
よし…　我が永遠のライバルに
化けるとは不敵なやつだ。
この手で化けの皮　剥いでやるぞ》
I'll strip his fake hide
with my very own hands!
お～い　今行くぞ！
Yeah, be right there.
よっ　大丈夫？　何があった？
Hey, how are things?
What happened?
よっ　大丈夫？　ときたか。
まるで　こちらから→
So, that's his line.
He's making it sound like
we sent a signal for help.
来てくれという救難信号でも
打ったような言いぐさだ。
そう　やすやすとはだまされんぞ。
But I won't be fooled so easily.
何があったとは　なんのことだ？
What do you mean,
"What happened?"
何がって　ほら
ＳＯＳくれたでしょ？
Well, you sent an SOS, didn't you?
べ～っ　バカめ！　そんな
見え透いたウソなどつきおって。
What a fool.
Telling such a bold-faced lie.
But attacking him out of
the blue is too childish.
しかし　いきなり攻撃するのも
大人気ない。
I'll wait until I have
irrefutable proof that he's a fake.
ニセモノである決定的な証拠を
つかんでからだ。
But how can I…?
しかし　どうやって…。
Is there anything between
Kakashi and me
俺とカカシのことで　敵が知りえない
情報は　何かないものかな…。
that an enemy couldn't
possibly know?
ん？
う～ん…。
そうだ　あれだ！
あれがあったぞ！
I know! That! There's that!
Oh, by the way…
おぉ　そういえば
俺とお前の　ライバル対決の勝敗。
How do we stand on
our rivalry battle?
あれは　何勝何敗に
なっていたっけな？
What's our win-loss record?
えっ？　ちょっと…。
What? This isn't the time
to discuss that.
今　そんなこと言ってる場合じゃ
ないんじゃないの？
I knew it!
やっぱりだ。
いくら　そっくりに化けても→
He may look identical,
but he couldn't have delved that
deeply into our private affairs.
そこまでプライベートな情報は
調べてなかったんだな。
I see, so you don't know.
そうか　知らんのか。
知らんのだなぁ…。
Well sure, I remember but…
いや　そりゃ　覚えてるけど。
なに？　知っているのか？
What? You know?
あぁ　当然でしょ。
Of course.
５１勝５０敗で　俺の勝ち越し…
でしょ？
I'm winning, 51-50. Right?
Yes! He finally gave
himself away!
やった！　ついに馬脚を現したぞ！
そんなことより
ＳＯＳの理由はなんなのよ？
But never mind that.
What was the reason for the SOS?
あぁ　危機は　すぐ目の前にある！
There's danger right
before my eyes.
木ノ葉　剛力旋風！
Severe Leaf Hurricanes!
What's the big idea?
いきなり　どうした！？
As expected.
さすが　カカシに変化するだけあって
素早いな！　せいっ！
You didn't just take on
Kakashi's appearance,
but his speed too!
Go!
いくら逃げても
俺の体術からは逃げ切れんぞ！
You can't escape my taijutsu,
no matter how much you run.
You didn't call me just to
continue our rivalry, did you?
まさか　ライバル勝負がしたくて
呼び出したんじゃないだろうね！？
上手く化けたもんだな。
You're a fine imitation.
If you're real,
then copy my taijutsu!
だが　正真正銘のコピー忍者カカシなら→
我が体術を
コピーしてみたらどうだ！
Just like
"Copy Ninja" Kakashi would!
お前　ホントにガイなの！？
Are you really Guy?
What did you say?
な　なんだと！？
The real Guy knows that
my Sharingan can't copy everything!
ガイだったら　写輪眼が
なんでもかんでも→
コピーできるわけじゃないこと
知ってるでしょ！
ニセモノのくせに
俺をニセモノ呼ばわりとは→
Just like an imposter to
accuse me of being the fake!
ニセモノふてぶてしいわ！
What's all the commotion?
いったい　何の騒ぎだ！？
It's Guy! I thought
I didn't see him around.
ガイさん！
姿が見えないと思ったら。
That doesn't sound like
something trivial. Let's go!
ただ事ではない様子ですね。
行ってみましょう。
ああ。
Right!
What can I say to
make you believe me?
どう言えば
信じてもらえるのかな？
あくまでも　しらばっくれる気か？
Are you going to keep denying it?
Guy!
ガイさん！
おう！　いいとこに来てくれた。
Oh, you're just in time!
Well, if it isn't Kakashi!
（ヤマト）カカシ先輩じゃないですか！
（カカシ）よう　元気だった？
Hey, how've you been?
おい！　やすやすと
だまされるやつがあるか！
Hey, don't let him fool you
so easily!
He's a fake posing as Kakashi!
こいつは　カカシのニセモノだ！
（ヤマト／アオバ）えぇっ！？
What?
No matter how you look at it,
he seems like the real Kakashi.
どう見ても
本物のカカシ先輩にしか見えない。
Yes. You're Kakashi, right?
ええ…　カカシさんですよね？
See? But he won't let me
off the hook.
ね？　さっきから　この調子で
困ってんだよ。
Don't be fooled, Yamato!
だまされるな　ヤマト！
It's just as you said.
お前が言っていたように
こいつ　チャクラまでも→
He even transformed
his chakra exactly into Kakashi's!
カカシそっくりに
変化させておるのだ。
And I have lots of proof!
ニセモノの証拠は
俺が　がっちり握っている！
Now, the three of us should…
さぁ　３人で…。
あ…　あっ！　お前ら！
Hey, you guys!
Did you ever consider that
ガイさんのほうが　敵の幻術にでも
かかってるんじゃ…。
you might be trapped in
the enemy's genjutsu?
Or maybe,
you're still not feeling well
それとも　連日の船酔いで
体調がおもわしくないのかも。
from being seasick
for days on end.
Right? He's not normal, is he?
ね？　まともじゃないでしょ？
So you'd rather side with
the impostor than listen to me?
お前たち　俺の言うことを聞かずに
ニセモノの言うことを…。
I see! I get it!
あっ　そうか！　そういうことか。
You're all fakes!
お前たち全員　ニセモノだな！？
やっぱ　おかしい。
木遁で　動きを封じておきます。
He really is acting strange.
I'll use my Wood Style to
hold down his movements.
As if I'd let you!
そうはさせるか！
八門遁甲　第六景門　開！
Eight Inner Gates!
Sixth Gate of Joy, open!
This is bad! He's serious!
（カカシ）やばい！　本気だ！
海中に逃げろ！
Dive into the sea
as deep as you can!
なるべく深くだ！
シャ～ッ！
朝孔雀！
Asakujaku!
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
（カカシ）いったい何が
ニセモノの証拠だっていうの？
Just what proof do you
have that I'm an impostor?
教えてやろう。
俺とカカシは永遠のライバルだ。
I'll tell you!
It has to do with our battles
as eternal rivals!
There is no way you would get
そのライバルが　対決の勝敗を
間違えるはずがない！
the win-loss record of
our battles wrong!
It's 51-50 in my favor,
there's no mistake.
５１勝５０敗で
俺の勝ち越しで間違いないよ。
Or maybe, you're just bitter that
それとも　この間のライバル対決で
俺が勝ち越したのが→
I took the lead after
our last match.
よっぽど悔しかったのかな？
なに？
What?
So you were watching that
battle from somewhere?!
どこかで見ていたんだな
あの勝負を。
How should I put it,
I'm the real one.
ていうか　本人だから。
ハッハッハッハッ！　ニセモノめ。
You fake!
あの勝負を入れて俺とカカシの勝負は
５０勝５０敗でタイなのだ　タイ。
That match tied us!
You and I are 50-50! Tied!
No, you're wrong.
いや　違うよ。
へっ？
Huh?
There was the sushi-eating
contest after that.
あのあとの回転寿司勝負でも
俺の勝ちだったでしょ。
Where I won right?
もう食えん…　ウェッ。
I can't eat another bite.
わ　忘れていた…。
I forgot about that!
いやいや！　それも
どこかで見ていたに違いない。
No! You must've been watching
that from afar too!
いいかげんにしてください。
死ぬところでしたよ。
Will you cut it out?
You almost killed us!
Then do you want me
to reveal your secret,
じゃあ　俺しか知らないお前の秘密
バラしちゃおうかな。
the one that only I would know?
ほう　おもしろい。
That's interesting.
そんな秘密などあったら
俺にも教えてほしいわ。
If you know of such a secret,
I'd like to know too!
What? Guy has such
a fine physique,
ガイさん　あんなに体格いいのに
ドングリサイズなんですか？
but it's the size of an acorn?
（アオバ）ちっちゃ。
小さな猛獣と呼ぼうかな。
That small? Maybe we should
call him the "Little Beast."
It's not like that anymore!
（ガイ）今は違う！　子供のときだ！
That was back
when I was a kid!
Kakashi, I really thought the enemy
had infiltrated us.
カカシ　すっかり敵が送り込んだ
ニセモノと勘違いしてしまったぞ。
だいたい
なぜ　お前がここにいるのだ？
What are you doing here anyway?
だから言ったでしょ。
ＳＯＳの忍亀をよこされたから→
I already told you!
You sent your Ninja Tortoise
SOS to us.
慌てて飛んできたわけなんだけど。
So I rushed on over.
えっ…　やっぱり
あのとき飛んでいったのは…。
So back then,
when something whizzed past us…
Guy was sending
his Ninja Tortoise out?
ガイさんの飛ばした忍亀…。
あのときって…　あっ。
That time? Oh!
ウェッ…　うっ…。
アイテッ！
カメ？
Ouch!
Turtle?
Help me.
助けてくれ…。
カメ…　カメ！
Turtle?
Turtle!
Hey, didn't something
just fly past us?
（ヤマト）あれ？　今
なんか飛んでいきませんでした？
（アオバ）あぁ　飛んだな。
Yeah, something did.
I'm sorry.
いやぁ　すまんすまん。
So you caused this, Guy.
原因を作ったのは
ガイさんだったんですね。
ハッハッハッ！
あ～　里の方は近頃どうよ？
How are things back
at the village?
話そらしてるし。
He just changed the subject.
Well, things have gotten
a bit complicated.
それが　ちょっと厄介なことに
なりそうなんだ。
どうした？
What's wrong?
I'll contact you again
once it's all decided.
いや　本決まりになってから
また　連絡するよ。
おお　そうか。
Oh, okay.
ところで
ナルトには会っていかないのか？
By the way, are you going
see Naruto before you go?
ああ。　お前がついてるし。
ああ　そうだな。
ガイ。
おう。
もし　俺に何かあったら
今度は　お前が駆けつけてくれよ。
当たり前だ。　心配するな。
ふぁ～。
なんか　カカシ先生の声がしたような。
あ～っ！
また俺だけのけもんにして！
やっぱり　うまいもん
隠してんだろ！
（アオバ）ないよ。
ウソだい！　こそこそ集まって
何してんだってばよ！
（ガイ）天体観測だ！
（アオバ）ドングリ観測だ。
（ガイ）星はちっちゃいな。
皆様　お変わり
ございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。